Hallelujah!
It is all about faith.
When we examine our daily life, we will find out how much faith we have.
When you examine your life, your daily life, you will be able to find out how much faith you have.
When somebody says, "I'm a Christian" I just laugh.
I am a Christian, I am a pastor, I am a bishop, I am this... but examine your daily life,
you will find out how much faith you have.
An empty profession of faith will not help us at all.
An empty one...
This is a life we live today, professional faith - empty.
I am a Christian, whereas you are not.
What can we show?
I am a Christian - this is an empty professional faith.
Faith is manifested in the small things in our daily life.
This means, by faith...
Because we have no other life as a Christian – faith.
You only apply faith when you need healing – that kind of faith is the kind of Christian you are.
You apply faith when you are in need of something from God.
God, help me, I have faith.
Even to sit down, you need faith to sit down.
To stand up - by faith.
To say Amen - by faith.
To greet - by faith.
Faith is manifested in the small things in our daily life.
Until you know how much you need God.
But you - you don't need God to sit down.
This is a big mistake.
You don't know how much you need God, and you claim you are a Christian.
How many of you actually sit in the name of Jesus, by the help of Jesus,
or, when you are standing up you say, thank you Jesus?
No, you don't need God for those things. You believe you can do them.
Tell your neighbour, “until you begin to know how much you need God.”
I cannot hear you.
Do you know that you need God to dress up?
Even to make a make-up.
You need God to comb your hair.
How many of you know this?
Do you know that you even need God to greet?
"How are you sir?" - you need God to say that.
Look at me - I need God to turn around.
I just need God to pick something from the ground.
But how many of you know this?
And you are saying you are serving God.
You say that you are serving God.
Satan lashes at you in the area you believe you don’t need God.
That is where satan attacks you.
Satan always attacks you where you believe you don't need God.
When you want to sit down, satan attacks you because he knows you would not call God to help you to sit.
When God is not involved your strength is zero.
Tell your neighbour, “satan attacks where we believe we don’t need God”.
"How are you?" - you believe you don't need God to say that.
Satan comes in.
He always monitors your life to study and know the area you do not involve God.
That is the area to which he will come and attack.
You want to pray... OK, I'm going to pray, wait for me...
While you are going you don't need God, until you get to where you want to pray,
but before that - satan strikes you.
Until you know how much you need God, then you serve God.
You don’t know how much you need God.
You think that you don't need God for small things and you need God for big things.
You need God when a doctor tells you, "go and write your will,
we can no longer treat you. Just eat and leave, but this case - nothing we can do."
Then you run to God.
But as long as the doctor tells you that they can handle your case - you don't need God.
You always come to God with a case where all hopes are lost.
Then you involve God.
You don't need God.
Until you know how much you need God, then you begin to live a wonderful life - a life of contentment.
Then you discover yourself – what God says you can do,
what God says you are and what God says you can achieve.
Do you know that you need God to look at me?
But you are looking at me without involving God.
My God, you are looking at me without involving God because you don't need God to look at me,
until you get blind.
When you get blind you say, "God, open my eyes to see this man".
Are you with me?
See, you are looking at me. You don't involve God to see me,
because you believe you don't need God to see me.
But when you are blind you involve God to open your eyes to see me.
Tell your neighbour, "until you know how much you need God".
Not mine not mine the choice
In things both great and small
Be Thou my Guide my Strength
My Wisdom my All
You may be seated.
Before your coming here today, your problems are above your strength.
You realize that you need to go to the Synagogue.
You were handling things yourself.
You thought that this thing could have been handled by you with no problem,
but it is above you, and you quickly have to run here.
You are welcome.
Until you know how much you need God.
I know how much I need God; that is why I pray all the time, 24/7.
I am always in an attitude of prayer.
Look at me, I'm calling God to help me to turn.
See, as I'm talking to you I'm talking to God to help me to turn.
I turn and I say "Thank you Jesus".
I need God to move my leg - "Oh God, thank you".
This is why I pray all the time.
Because you don’t know how much you need God, that is why you have a time, when and how to pray.
Big situations happen occasionally but little situations happen all the time.
Look at me, because I have not called God to be involved - I cannot move.
OK, now - "God, thank you - I am moving".
See, at the same time I am talking I pray "thank you for Your strength to talk".
I am turning again and I pray "thank you Lord, give me the strength to turn".
If I want to sleep I would do the same.
All the time - I pray all the time, because I need Him in all I do.
I know how much I need Him.
I need Him to be involved in everything I do.
Then - there is no time to break.
Your problem is you don't know how much you need God.
Those areas you believe you don’t need God are the areas the satan uses to enter.
That is avenue for satan, the route for satan – those areas you believe you don’t need God.
You create an avenue and opportunity for satan to enter you.
At the time you think you don't need God - satan has entered already.
He has used these small things you believed you could do yourself, whereas you don't have any strength.
Those things you believe you can do yourself, it is not you – you don't have strength to do anything.
Tell your neighbour, "How much you need God".
You need to know how much you need God.
I cannot hear you.
Again and again.
You need to know how much you need God.
Stand up now. Are you calling God to stand up? That is the problem.
Where did you get the strength to stand up? From God. But why are you not involving Him?
It means you are using your own strength to stand up.
I can see the reason why you have the spinal cord injury.
Let us stand up.
Sit down. Are you involving God?
Yes.
For the first time.
When you begin to recognize and to know that you need God even in the small things...
Faith is manifested in the small things in our daily life.
If you want to overcome and become victorious in this word, you must know how much you need God.
Can you greet your colleague? Give a handshake to your colleague.
Are you involving God?
Can you do that yourself?
You are involving God.
Yes.
Smile. Are you involving God to smile?
Take this from me: it shall be well with you!
Amen!
Satan is a very crafty person, trickish and tactical.
You have to involve God.
Those areas you fail to involve God are the areas satan is using.
You don't need to say, "I must pray before I sleep", if you have been praying already.
Sitting on the bed you have to involve God.
Laying and stretching your head on the the pillow you involve God.
When you lie down, you begin to meditate before you fall asleep.
You are praying before you stand up and go somewhere...
Then, there is no way for satan.
Those areas you find difficult to penetrate in your career, business, health or even marriage...
The One who watches over you never sleeps; why are you sleeping?
If you don't pray, you are sleeping.
He is watching over you 24/7.
You have to call Him 24/7; you have to involve Him 24/7.
As you are looking at me, are you involving God?
Something is going on in your heart, "Thank You, Jesus!"
Just, "Thank You, Jesus!" is enough.
It is just enough.
"Thank you Jesus" - as you are looking at me.
It means you are involving Him.
"Thank You, Jesus", but I do not understand what this man is saying.
Please, give me an understanding.
"Thank You, Jesus" - just thank You, Jesus.
You want to sit down - "Thank You Jesus".
You stand up - "Thank You, Jesus".
You want to dance - "Thank You, Jesus".
You can start from there - "Thank You, Jesus".
When He hears your thanks, He will open the relationship for you; He will give you a Word to say.
"Thank You, Jesus" - look at me, I am moving.
You cannot see my lips moving but I am saying something.
What I am saying is, "Thank You, Jesus".
But you will never see me because I am not involving my flesh, my body.
I never involve them to say that so therefore, it is possible for me to do other things on the outside.
It is when I involve my body to say "thank You, Jesus", and you are now calling me,
I would not be able to answer you.
"Thank You, Jesus" - if I want to answer you, I need to stop saying "thank You, Jesus".
Ehe - what are you saying?
It is because I am involving my flesh.
We are fighting spirit beings.
If our weapon of warfare were carnal, I would need to give you a gun and cutlass.
But our weapon of warfare is not carnal because we are fighting spirit beings.
Even when I am moving now - I am giving and I am receiving.
If I am only giving, and I am not receiving I would be dry
OK, see me.
I am giving you, but I must receive.
To receive, my heart must involve with God.
While I am giving, I receive.
I give, I am being filled.
You give but you do not receive.
Faith is a believer's heart.
Tell your neighbour.
Again.
Faith is a believer's heart.
It is a believer's heart - that is faith.
If someone asks you, "what is faith?" - you say, "faith is a believer's heart".
Someone say, "faith is to expect God to do what He is expected to do".
That is the definition.
It is simple - faith is a believer's heart.
And when you live by faith, walk by faith, talk by faith...
I can be going, you listen to me and I am talking to God.
If I want to talk to you I say "how are you?", but at the same time I am talking to God,
because my heart is faith.
If I want to talk to you, it does not mean I should stop talking to God;
I can be talking to God and at the same time, talking to you.
Yes, because it is my heart.
Lord I want to be like Jesus inner my heart
Inner my heart
That is why you can have any form of face; oval face, round face, be tall, fat, yellow, red, green,
but in our hearts, we are like Jesus.
A believer's heart is faith.
Inner my heart
Lord I want to be like Jesus inner my heart
Once again.
Inner my heart
Lord I want to be like Jesus inner my heart
Christianity lies in our hearts.
Begin to think about yourself.
Many of us are worshipping a God we do not know.
You never heard from Him before;
He never talked with you or acted with you and you never acted with Him.
You talk and act with Him by imagination.
Don't forget, while you are sitting down to say, "Thank You, Jesus" in your heart.
And begin to "fire-on" as you are looking at me, because as I am looking at you, I am fire.
What I say is what I receive, but I should also receive as I am giving you.
So, to receive from Him as I give you, my Spirit-man should also continue to "fire-on".
Begin to talk, "thank You, Jesus. I need more to give them".
As I give you my Spirit-man receives from Jesus, so I would not be "empty".
You may be seated, thank you.
Are you depending on Jesus to sit? What are you saying? "Thank You, Jesus".
Thank You, Jesus.
He loves it when you recognise Him, when you know He is your Lord and put Him where He belongs.
He is not one of those things; He is the only.
You make your plan. At the end of the day you say, "OK, I want to go to the church,
and I have to come back by 12 and go to the meeting".
You are making Him one of those things.
He is the only.
When you make a plan for the only one, do not miss that plan.
He is not a tenant, He is the landlord.
The challenge we have today is our upbringing.
Upbringing is still there.
We have not disconnected from upbringing in terms of our spiritual life.
Upbringing.
You are not yet what God says you are; you are like someone.
You look like somebody; your achievement is like somebody.
You talk like somebody; your behaviour is like somebody.
Your achievement can be compared with somebody - this is how he behaves.
That is why they don't miss you when you are not around,
because there are many people around who can do what you are doing.
You should be unique.
You are sent to make a difference.
You are pursuing what others have pursued.
What others have achieved is what you want to achieve.
You are not unique in any way.
If there is any uniqueness in your life - let me know.
Maybe your hair - you have blond hair, or you look tall, you are beautiful, or you are very rich,
there is no one as rich as you are, or you are an eloquent speaker.
No, you are not unique in any way. You are just like others. And why?
This is why the world is stagnant.
There were no differences in the world for past many years.
Since I was born I cannot see any difference in the world - the world is still the same.
Scientists cannot have a breakthrough any more. There is a trouble in the world.
There is no difference in the economy, no breakthrough in economy, no breakthrough in science,
no breakthrough in any area.
When we don’t have breakthrough, we continue to go around the cycle of life.
What we have used is what we keep using.
The idea we applied in the past is the same idea we are still applying.
The same idea.
In these days we talk of ideas appearing in the last 50 years.
Where were discoveries in different areas of life, but there is nothing like this any more.
Where are we going?
When you go to the airport you learn that there is no aircraft any more.
The little aircraft we have all over the world are damaged.
There is no a new one.
The exploitation of the one they discovered 5 years ago was stopped,
because it caused crisis and accidents all around the world.
The solar energy that you are talking about seems to be not reliable.
It is not yet confirmed, that the world can rely on that.
There is a crisis in the world.
There are no more discoveries.
We keep using old ideas, recycling...
Where are we going?
I will give you just a second or two minutes to think about your life.
Are you from Europe? Are you from Asia? Where are you from? Are you from Africa?
OK, sit down and think if there is any discovery in the world in your area.
We are running out of ideas.
The world is running out of ideas because we fail to carry God along.
We fail to know how much we need God.
You need to know how much you need God.
You need God to take a bath.
You need God to make up.
You need God to rub a cream.
You need God to look at the mirror.
The moment you know how much you need God, you are with God 24/7.
A break in God is a relationship with satan.
Just a break with God is a relationship with satan because there is no vacuum, no neutral world.
It is either you are dark or you are light.
When you are out of light, you are in darkness.
You may not confess satan but your faith is not practical.
Faith must be practical.
You must exercise your faith to show you believe because the belief in your heart is released by faith.
If I say I believe - to show I believe, my faith must be practised.
If I believe, where is my faith?
I believe Jesus Christ is my Lord and Saviour.
You believe Jesus is Saviour and your Lord. Where is your faith?
Faith is practical.
There is not abstract faith.
It must be practised.
If you have faith that is not practical, definitely, you have no faith.
"I believe" - where is your faith?
The belief in our heart can only be released by faith.
The question now: Are you a Christian?
Yes – it means you believe Jesus is your Lord and Saviour.
Yes – OK, show me your Saviour by faith.